Welcome to the overview of alpha factors.
欢迎学习 alpha 因子课程
This is the extra exciting part where you finally get to start
这节课非常精彩 你终于有机会
turning hypotheses into code and testing that code against data.
将假设变成代码并根据数据测试代码
Alpha factors are tools operating on data that give us
Alpha 因子是一种数据处理工具
signals about how stocks may perform relative to one another.
可以告诉我们股票相对于其他股票的业绩
You've heard a little about alpha factors already and how they differ from risk factors.
你已经听说过 alpha 因子 知道它们与风险因子有何区别
Remember that alpha factors are hopefully predictive of future mean returns,
注意 alpha 因子也许能预测未来均值收益率
while risk factors impart information about commonality of return variance.
而风险因子可以提供关于收益率方差共性方面的信息
The search for alpha factors is essentially
寻找 alpha 因子其实就是寻找
the search for deviations from the efficient market hypothesis.
偏离有效市场假说的信号
The efficient market hypothesis has different forms,
有效市场假说有不同的形式
but generally it means that
但通常是指
all available information is reflected in the current price of an asset,
所有可用的信息都体现在了资产的当前价格上
which suggests that assets are priced fairly.
表明资产的价格比较合理
When searching for exceptions to the efficient market hypothesis,
在寻找有效市场假说的例外情况时
we're looking for mispricing in the market.
我们寻找的是市场错误定价
We learned about arbitrage before,
我们之前学过套利
which is the simultaneous buying and selling of a perfect substitute to make a profit.
即同时买入和卖出一个完美的替代品并获利
In the context of this lesson,
在这节课
we'll also use the term arbitrage.
我们也会用到套利一词
But here, it refers to buying an asset that may be
但是指买入可能定价过低的资产
underpriced or shorting one that may be overpriced,
或做空可能定价过高的资产
where the expected return is in excess of what it should be for the risk we bear.
预期收益率超出了所承担的风险应该带来的收益率
In this lesson, we'll start by discussing
在这节课 我们将讨论学术研究成果
academic research as a source for hypotheses and for alpha factor generation.
并根据这些成果制定假说和生成 alpha 因子
We'll cover techniques for processing a raw alpha factor including methods,
我们将介绍处理原始 alpha 因子的技巧
such as sector neutralization, ranking,
包括各种方法 例如横截面中性化 排名
Z-scoring, smoothing, and conditioning factors on other factors.
Z 评分 平滑法和以其他因子为条件
Each of these techniques is important in
每种技巧都很重要
the process of turning the numbers in our alpha vectors into
可以指导我们将 alpha 因子中的数字变成信号
signals that represent whether to buy or short each stock in a portfolio and by how much.
这些信号表示是否买入或做空投资组合中的每支股票以及金额是多少
That is to say, these techniques are relevant to
这些技巧能够帮助我们实现
the goals that we have for real-world portfolios.
为真实投资组合设定的目标
We'll also cover techniques for evaluating factors,
我们还会介绍评估因子的技巧
such as the sharpe ratio,
例如夏普比率
information coefficient, information ratio, and turnover analysis.
信息系数 信息比率和周转率分析
These will help you decide whether your alphas provide enough return relative to risk,
这些指标有助于确定 alpha 因子相对于风险来说能否提供足够的收益率
and whether they will cause too much trading to likely be profitable in the real world.
以及是否会导致太多交易 在现实中不太可能获利
The topics we discuss here will prepare you for the following lesson,
刚刚讨论的话题将为接下来的课程打下基础
in which we extract alpha factor ideas from academic research papers,
届时我们将从学术研究论文中发现 alpha 因子理念
and then implement those ideas in code.
并用代码实现这些理念
This is exactly the type of work that quants do in the real world.
这些工作正是量化分析师需要完成的工作
In this lesson, we step into the typical life of a quant researcher.
在这节课 我们将走进量化研究员的日常生活当中
You'll see how quants generate alpha factor ideas
你将了解量化分析师如何提出 alpha 因子理念
that may make their way into real hedge fund portfolios.
这些理念也许会被真实的对冲基金投资组合采用